Finding Aid for the Kathy Sawyer Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
Kathy Sawyer Papers
2014
undated
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
MSS.0776
23.3 Linear Feet
Biographical Sketch
Soon after graduating from Vanderbilt University (BA ’64), Kathy began her journalism career as a feature writer for The Tennessean. She covered the music industry and a wide variety of other subjects. In 1970, she won the National Headliner Award for Best Domestic News Reporting for coverage of topics as varied as the war in Vietnam and East Tennessee chicken catches.
In 1976 Kathy went to work as a staff writer for The Washington Post. In 28 years at the paper, Kathy covered politics, social issues, and the federal government, among other topics. She left the paper in 2004. For her final 17 years there, she focused on space science and technology, beginning with the 1986 Challenger accident that killed seven astronauts. Her work has also been published in magazines such as National Geographic and Astronomy. She tracked space science on subjects from human space flight, to planets, to the use of satellites to monitor climate change. Twice nominated for the Pulitzer Prize, her honors include the David N. Schramm Award for journalism (1999), given by the American Astronomical Society. In 1992, Sawyer became the first woman to win the National Space Writer of the Year Award. In 2007, the National Academies of Sciences, Engineering and Medicine, the nation’s premier scientific advisory body, selected her book, The Rock from Mars: A Detective Story on Two Planets (Random House, 2006), as one of the three best books of the year.
Kathy has appeared as a guest on CBS’s “Face the Nation,” PBS’s “Lehrer News Hour” and “Washington Week,” and in news programming on C-Span and other TV outlets, as well as on radio programs such as NPR’s “Diane Rehm” show. She has also served the journalistic and scientific communities alike by participating in various industry panels and award committees.
In order to give readers a visceral sense of the events she writes about, Kathy has made parachute jumps, flown weightless aboard NASA’s “vomit comet” aircraft used to train astronauts, flown through the eye of a killer hurricane aboard a research plane, and is one of few journalists to make a deep ocean dive aboard the three-person Alvin submersible vessel in order to see oases of strange life thriving on the sunless floor of the Pacific.
Throughout their 34 years of marriage, Kathy and her husband John Atkisson, a trial lawyer, enjoyed sailing their boat Kestrel, a 32-foot sloop, in the waters of Chesapeake Bay and environs, and sometimes further. Kathy, John and their cat Beacon were at home on Capitol Hill on February 19, 2010, when John died of lung cancer.
Scope and Contents
The Kathy Sawyer Papers are composed of 7.5 linear feet of research, writings, interviews, correspondence and photographs from her career in journalism. The dates of the collection are from 1968 to 2007 and contain most of the writings Sawyer produced during that period.
Personal Information: Includes notes, photos, and clippings from newspaper coverage of Sawyers life events including marriage, injury, and awards.
Human Space Flight, 1986-2000: Includes notes, documents, interviews, pictures, and reports regarding Sawyer’s research around human space flight. Extensive notes from Sawyer’s interviews with Neil Armstrong and the International Space Station are included in this section. The Moon, 1994-1998: Includes notes, documents, interviews, pictures, and reports regarding
Sawyer’s Moon research.
Mars, 1992-2001: Includes notes, documents, interviews, pictures, and reports regarding Sawyer’s Mars research.
Jupiter, 1995-2000: Includes notes, documents, interviews, pictures, and reports regarding Sawyer’s Jupiter research.
Neptune/Saturn/Pluto, 1997-2000: Includes notes, documents, interviews, pictures, and reports regarding Sawyer’s research on the outer planets.
Asteroids, 1991-2001: Includes notes, documents, pictures articles, and reports regarding Sawyer’s asteroid research.
Extra Solar/Cosmology, 1992-2000: Includes notes, documents, pictures, and reports regarding Sawyer’s research around cosmology and planets.
Climate Change, 1993-1996: Includes notes, documents, and reports regarding Sawyer’s research on weather and climate change, including coverage of the weather at the 1996 Olympics.
Health, 1994: Includes notes, documents, interviews, and reports regarding Sawyer’s research on the NIC’s clinical trials.
Freelance: Includes notes, documents, interviews, pictures, reports, and scripts regarding Sawyer’s work for ABC, National Geographic, and others.
Articles, 1974-2007: Includes clippings of articles written by Sawyer as well as clips and bylines for Pulitzer.
The Washington Post, 1975-1999: Includes full issues of the Washington Post containing articles written by Sawyer.
Audio/Visual, 1998-2003: Includes cassettes, microcassettes, VHS tapes, CDs, and slides with interview recordings, debates, conferences and hearings as well as images.
Provenance Statement
This collection was donated by Kathy Sawyer in 2012 with additions in 2015 and 2016
Provenance Statement
Permission to publish, copy, reprint, digitize, orally record for transmission over public or private airways, or use material from the Kathy Sawyer Papers in any and all other current or future developed methods or procedures, must be obtained in writing from the Special Collections and University Archives Division of the Vanderbilt University Libraries. All rights are reserved and retained regardless of current or future development or laws that may apply to fair use standards
- Personal
  - Kathy Sawyer Bios (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Kathy Sawyer – Personal Info (1) (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Kathy Sawyer – Personal Info (2) (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Kathy Sawyer – Personal Info (3) (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Kathy Sawyer – Personal Info (4) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Foreign Travel Brochures (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Nashville SPJ Panel, 1993 (1) (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Nashville SPJ Panel, 1993 (2) (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Knight Fellowship, MIT, 1995, notes (1) (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Knight Fellowship, MIT, 1995, notes (2) (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Knight Fellowship, MIT, 1995, notes (3) (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - American University Extraterrestrial Life Panel Speech, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - 1st Amendment Center Roundtable, Nashville, TN, notes, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Vanderbilt National Advisory Board, 1999-2000 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - AAAS COPUST Acceptance, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Personal
  - Kathy Sawyer Bios (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Clips and Bylines – Pulitzer Prep (1) (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Clips and Bylines – Pulitzer Prep (2) (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Clips and Bylines – Pulitzer Prep (3) (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Schram Award Entry, 1999-2000 (1) (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Schram Award Entry, 1999-2000 (2) (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence (1) (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence (2) (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence (3) (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence (4) (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Fan mail and Notes (1) (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Fan mail and Notes (2) (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - American Astronomical Society Meeting, 2006 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Space Flight
  - Pressures within NASA – notes, April-May 1986 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - “Space Shuttle Explodes, Killing Crew,”, January 1986 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Challenger – Press Kit, Flight Chart (pre-explosion), 1986 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Challenger – Engine Images (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Challenger Aftermath, notes, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Challenger Aftermath – Interview, December 1986 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Challenger Anniversary Series, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - The New York Times, Challenger Series, September 1988 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Space Shuttle – notes (1) (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Space Shuttle – notes (2) (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - “Morton Thiokol” – copy, November 1986 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - “Partispace” – copy, January 1987 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Morton Thiokol “MT Nozzle” – copy, February 1988 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - “Satellite” – copy, May 1988 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Nuclear Power in Space – notes (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - NASA Safety – notes (1) (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - NASA Safety – notes (2) (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - “Galileo” – copy, September 1989 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Sally Ride – notes (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - “Topaz” – copy, December 1992 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Space Flight
  - Telescope Tour – notes, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - “Space Toilets” – copy, December 1992 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Space Toilets – notes (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - NASA “hits,” weaknesses – notes (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - NASA weaknesses – notes (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - NASP – notes (1) (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - NASP – notes (2) (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - NASP – notes (3) (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - NASP – notes (4) (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - NASP – notes (5) (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Speech Notes, 1990-1992 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - SpySats – notes, 1990-1993 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Declassified SpySats Intelligence (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - SpySats – notes, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - K.C. Thornton – notes (1) (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - K.C. Thornton – notes (2) (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - K.C. Thornton – notes (3) (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - “Small Sat” Approach to Space, 1993-1994 (1) (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - “Small Sat” Approach to Space, 1993-1994 (2) (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - “Small Sat” Approach to Space, 1993-1994 (3) (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - “Small Sat” Approach to Space, 1993-1994 (4) (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Private Satellite Notion, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - STS-71 – notes (1) (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - STS-71 – notes (2) (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - STS-71 – notes (3) (Box 4, Folder 25)
- Space Flight
  - STS-71 – notes (4) (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - STS-71 – notes (5) (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - STS-71 – notes (6) (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - STS-71 – notes (7) (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - US Launch Policy, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - US Launch Policy, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - US Launch Policy, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Space Shuttle Launch Kits (1) (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Space Shuttle Launch Kits (2) (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Space Shuttle Launch Kits (3) (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - CBS News Space Reporter’s Handbook (1) (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - CBS News Space Reporter’s Handbook (2) (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - CBS News Space Reporter’s Handbook (3) (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - CBS News Space Reporter’s Handbook (4) (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - CBS News Space Reporter’s Handbook (5) (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - CBS News Space Reporter’s Handbook (6) (Box 5, Folder 16)
- Space Flight
  - CBS News Space Reporter’s Handbook (7) (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - CBS News Space Reporter’s Handbook (8) (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - CBS News Space Reporter’s Handbook (9) (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - CBS News Space Reporter’s Handbook (10) (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Liberty Bell-7 Recovery – notes, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Discovery-MIR Partnership – copy, December 1995 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Discovery-MIR Partnership – notes (1) (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Discovery-MIR Partnership – notes (2) (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Discovery-MIR Partnership – notes (3) (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Discovery-MIR Partnership – notes (4) (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - NASA – Shuttle Safety, 1996-1997 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - X-33 Briefing – notes, November 1996 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - STS-95 Pre-landing – notes (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Tethered Satellites – notes (1) (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Tethered Satellites – notes (2) (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - NASA – Shutdown, 1996 (Box 6, Folder 16)
- Space Flight
  - Solar Eclipse, 1991 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - SETI, 1989-1995 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Manned Space Flight, General (1) (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Manned Space Flight, General (2) (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - STS-88 – notes (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Small-Sat Approach, 1993-1994 (1) (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Small-Sat Approach, 1993-1994 (2) (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Small-Sat Approach, 1993-1994 (3) (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Small-Sat Approach, 1993-1994 (4) (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Orbital Debris –, 1989-1997 (1) (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Orbital Debris –, 1989-1997 (2) (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Private Satellite Motion, 1994 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Space Transport, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Freelance, Snowball Earth, 1998-1999 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Snowball Earth Images (Box 7, Folder 15)
- Space Flight
  - Challenger Aftermath – clippings, notes (1) (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Challenger Aftermath – clippings, notes (2) (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - The New Yorker, Space History (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - “Space Sex” – copy, September, 2000 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Sex in Space – notes (1) (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Sex in Space – notes (2) (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Sex in Space – notes (3) (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Russian space station MIR de-orbit, 2001 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Spacesuits and John Glenn (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - John Glenn – interview, August 1998 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Pete Conrad Death, 1999 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - International Space Station – Safety (1) (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - International Space Station – Safety (2) (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - International Space Station – Safety (3) (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - International Space Station – Safety (4) (Box 8, Folder 15)
- Space Flight
  - International Space Station – technical documents – medical hardware catalog (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - International Space Station – technical documents – equipment, acronyms (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - International Space Station – technical documents – equipment recovery (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - CAIB Briefing, 2003 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Columbia – aluminum fire (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Columbia – foam impact tests (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Columbia – assent/entry (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Columbia – post-accident interviews (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Columbia – notes (1) (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Columbia – notes (2) (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Columbia—notes (3) (Box 9, Folder 11)
- Space Flight
  - Houston Interviews – post Columbia, 2003 (1) (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Houston Interviews – post Columbia, 2003 (2) (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Houston Gehman Interviews – post Columbia, 2003 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Houston NASA HQ Roundtable, 2003 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Houston FOAM Impact Test, 2003 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Houston NASA Budgets, 2004 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Columbia – internal emails (1) (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Columbia – internal emails (2) (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Columbia – internal emails (3) (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Columbia – first anniversary/policy (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Space Station – draft (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Space Station – notes (1) (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Space Station – notes (2) (Box 10, Folder 13)
- Space Flight
  - Space Station – Orbital Mechanics of Docking (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Space Station – Art (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Space Station – workshop, 1998 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Space Station – notes, 1998 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Space Station – notes, 1999 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Space Station – STS – notes, drafts—, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Space Station – notes, drafts (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Space Station – EVA (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Space Station – Zvezda—notes, drafts (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Space Station – notes, drafts (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Space Station – notes, drafts (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Space Station – notes, drafts (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Space Station – notes, drafts (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Space Station – interviews and briefings, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Space Station – documents, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Space Station – clips, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 16)
- Space Flight
  - Space Station – notes (1) (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Space Station – notes (2) (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Space Station – notes (3) (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Space Station – notes (4) (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Space Station – notes (5) (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Space Station – notes (6) (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Space Station – notes (7) (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Space Station – notes (8) (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Space Station – notes (9) (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Space Station – US/Russian Partnership – notes (1) (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Space Station – US/Russian Partnership – notes (2) (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Space Station – US/Russian Partnership – notes (3) (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Space Station – US/Russian Partnership – notes (4) (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Space Station – US/Russian Partnership – notes (5) (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Space Station – US/Russian Partnership – notes (6) (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Space Station – US/Russian Partnership – notes (7) (Box 12, Folder 16)
- International Space Flight/Books
  - Space Station – US/Russian Partnership – notes (8) (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Space Station – US/Russian Partnership – notes (9) (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Space Station – US/Russian Partnership – notes (10) (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Space Station – US/Russian Partnership – notes (11) (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Space Station – letters received (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Space Station, power – notes (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Space Station, power – notes (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - NRC Re: Space Station (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Space Station – scientist interviews (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Worlds Apart (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - The Soviet Year in Space, 1985 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - The Soviet Year in Space, 1986 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - The Soviet Space Challenge, Pioneering the Space Frontier (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Watergate (Box 13, Folder 14)
- Books
  - Legislative Origins of the National Aeronautics and Space Act of, 1958 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Apollo 12 – The NASA Mission (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - TOPS: Towards Other Planetary (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Scientific Prerequisites for the Human Exploration of (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Report of the Workshop on Biology-Based Technology to Enhance Human Well-Being and Function in Extended Space (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Science and Technology Shaping the (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - 2002 Aerospace (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Mars Direct: The Red Planet in Ten Years; Smithsonian Astrophysical (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Minnesota in the Civil and Indian Wars – Documentary (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Hubble 2005: Science Year in (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Oceanus 27.4, 1984 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Oceanus 35.4, 1992/93 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Exploring the Universe with the Hubble Space (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Cosmic Journey: To the Edge of Gravity, Space, and Time; Structure & Evolution of the Universe Roadmap, 2003-2023 (Box 14, Folder 14)
- Books
  - Mars Observer Loss of Signal: Special Review Board Final Repor (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Biological Contamination of Mars: Issues and (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Report of the HST Strategy Panel: A Strategy for (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Experimental Gerontology 26.2/3, 1991 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - The Voyager Neptune Travel (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Protecting the Space Station from Meteoroids and Orbital (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Round Trip to Orbit: Human Spaceflight Alternatives, Special (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Galileo: Exploration of Jupiter’s (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - America at the Threshold: America’s Space Exploration (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Report of the Advisory Committee on the Future of the U.S. Space (Box 15, Folder 10)
- The Moon
  - Clementine Moon Mission – notes, 1994 (1) (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Clementine Moon Mission – notes, 1994 (2) (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Clementine Moon Mission – notes, 1994 (3) (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Clementine Moon Mission – notes, 1994-1996 (4) (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Clementine Moon Mission – notes, 1994-1996 (5) (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Clementine – moon images (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Lunar Exploration – NASA docs (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Apollo Mission – NASA docs (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Apollo 11 – NASA docs (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Apollo Lunar Service Report (1) (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Apollo Lunar Service Report (2) (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Lunar Imagine (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Lunar Update – notes, 1998 (1) (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Lunar Update – notes, 1998 (2) (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - Lunar Update – notes, 1998 (3) (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - Lunar Imaging (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - Apollo 20th Anniversary (Box 16, Folder 17)
- The Moon/Mars
  - Apollo anniversary, 1999 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Neil Armstrong feature – drafts and photos (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Neil Armstrong feature – notes (1) (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Neil Armstrong feature – notes (2) (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Neil Armstrong records (1) (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Neil Armstrong records (2) (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Neil Armstrong records (3) (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Astronauts (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Astronaut Wolf’s letters from orbit (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Space art (Box 17, Folder 10)
- Mars
  - The Case for Mars by Robert Zubrin with Richard Wagner, 1996 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Contacts (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Mars Observer failure investigation, September 1992-October 18, 1993 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Mars Observer failure investigation, October 19, 1993-March 1995 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Mars Observer failure investigation, Undated notes (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Mars Observer failure investigation – Executive summary (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Russian Space Probe failure, 1996 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Pathfinder Landing, 1996 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Pathfinder Landing, March-June 1997 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Pathfinder Landing, July 1997 (Box 18, Folder 10)
- Mars
  - Pathfinder Landing, August 1997-1998 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Pathfinder Landing, undated (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Mars Global Surveyor Arrival, 1997 (1) (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Mars Global Surveyor Arrival, 1997 (2) (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Missions, 1996-1997 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Cyclonia (face) update, April 6, 1998 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Donna Shirley interviews, 1998 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Mars – Missions, 1998 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Missions – 1998 Rock life signs (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - 1998 Mars Mission (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Mars – Art (Box 19, Folder 11)
- Space Flight
  - Mission documents, 1996-1997 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Mars Observer research, 1994 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Mars – rover, discoveries – notes, research, 1997-2003 (1) (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Mars – rover, discoveries – notes, research, 1997-2003 (1) (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Mars Images (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Hubble Images of Mars (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Mars Images, 2003 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Mars Drafts/Clips, 2004 (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Mars Rover Landings, 2004 (1) (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Mars Rover Landings, 2004 (2) (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Freedom of Information Act (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Mars—Art (Box 20, Folder 12)
- Mars
  - Mars landers, 1998 and 1999 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Mars Orbiter investigation, 1999 (1) (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Mars Orbiter investigation, 1999 (2) (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Mars Lander investigation – assessment team report, March 14, 2000 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Mars Lander investigation – report, March 22, 2000 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Mars Lander investigation – notes and articles, March 2000 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - NEAR – notes (1) (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - NEAR – notes (2) (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - NEAR – notes (3) (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Odyssey, 2001 (Box 21, Folder 10)
- Jupiter
  - Galileo – notes, 1995 (1) (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Galileo – notes, 1995 (2) (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Galileo – notes, 1995 (3) (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Galileo – notes, 1995 (4) (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Galileo – notes, 1995 (5) (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Galileo – notes, 1995 (6) (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Galileo – notes, 1995 (7) (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Galileo – imaging (1) (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Galileo – imaging (2) (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - Europa – notes, 1997 (1) (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Europa – notes, 1997 (2) (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - Jupiter System – notes (1) (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - Jupiter System – notes (2) (Box 22, Folder 13)
  - Jupiter Rings – notes, drafts, 1998 (Box 22, Folder 14)
  - Europa Water – notes, 2000 (1) (Box 22, Folder 15)
  - Europa Water – notes, 2000 (2) (Box 22, Folder 16)
  - Europa Water – notes, 2000 (3) (Box 22, Folder 17)
  - Europa Water – notes, 2000 (4) (Box 22, Folder 18)